I'm going to introduce you to the platform
SNITEM OPALE that I had the opportunity to
during my permanent contract at Soft Concept
for almost a year. Opale
is a tool for managing the
different stages to get the
MDR certification. So MDR is for
Medical Device Regulation and
Snitem is the French National Union of
the medical technology industry.
Then it is not the Snitem that provides
certification, but it is well under its
initiative that the member manufacturers
will proceed with the different stages
in order to obtain this certification.
Two types of profiles for the application,
on the one hand, administrator or Snitem and
on the other hand, manufacturer or adherent.
The Snitem administrator or user
will be able to have a macro view
and possibly have a
ability to manage access:
manufacturers and users who
represent them. The
manufacturer, he will be able to
enter data, therefore
financial data,
market data,
general data.
And with this data that it will provide,
it will feed a micro dashboard
that a decision-maker will be able to consult.
And it will also feed
the macro table that can be seen by the
SNITEM users or
platform administrators.
If I log in as an administrator.
So, administrator. The difference
between the administrator and a SNITEM
profile, even though the
functionality remains almost identical,
the SNITEM will not have
user management
,the manufacturers being the
device Producers
whether it is medicines,
prosthetics, et cetera.
So there the administrator profile will
have the macro chart
Diagnostic status compound, decision,
monitoring and access management. So there
we have the number of registered
companies, the number of
created products, the number of TDs created.
So a TD is a technical
documentation
We also have the decision. So there, it's a
dynami reporting
of the status of the TDs for example, the
piloting, manufacturers
and users. So, SNITEM,
we have the same menus
without access management and
we also have a guide
so as to use the platform
quite detailed with the notions a little
complicated that are addressed
in this platform. Knowing that the
platform is intended to respect
ISO standard
for medical
software. So for a
manufacturer, there will be
the ability to import data via
an Excel file. So we have a form
Excel of the model and we will be able to
download here and drop it off.
It goes automatically
feed products, QMS or TD. Then
QMS in fact is the
quality management system.
And TD, as I said earlier,
it's Technical Documentation, MD
being Medical Devices.
So we can create new products.
You can also display or not the
different columns. So, for example,
for a product.
For example, a suction probe
tracheal. So here, we
will be able to fill in the different
product data, so the data
for example, the
market data,
technical data and
free comments.
We will also be able to
Associate a product with a TD.
We will also be able to delete
the different associations.
You can also remove the product. For
the QMS, it's going to be the same principle so
there will also be data to be
to fill. So financial data,
technical, regulatory and steering
for a regulatory
decision and an audit that
will take place to make the transition
between the MDD and the MDR. MDR is the
new regulation, MDD is
the old one.
We will also have data on the
steering with a percentage
update. We will be able to delete
the QMS.
For the TDs, we will have different
status, in transition,
new. We will also be able to
provide data on the diagnostic
status, on the SMQ/TD/
products, managing the TD
and tracking monitoring
statistics.
In the monitoring, we'll see
the overall progress of the TD, whether
the deadlines have been met, if
the evaluation was planned...
The milestones, so the current date, the
expiry date of the MDD
certificate.
Data can also be filled in
on the company,
in particular the size of the company,
French capitals and
total business capital.
We can disconnect.